Guide to the New Haven and Connecticut Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, and Transgender Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
New Haven and Connecticut lesbian, gay, bisexual, and transgender collection
1972-2007
MS 1878
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
10.75
(20 boxes)
This intentionally assembled collection documents lesbian, gay, bisexual, and transgender people, organizations, and events in New Haven and Connecticut. The collection consists of newsletters, flyers, posters, and other printed material.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Frank Gagliardi and various donors, 2006-2009. Boxes 17 and 18 transferred from RU 963 (Accession 2005-A-060), 2004. Boxes 19 and 20 transferred from the Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library, 2010.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in two series: I. Publications, 1972-2007. II. Organizations, 1978-2007.
Scope and Contents
This intentionally assembled collection documents lesbian, gay, bisexual, and transgender people, organizations, and events in New Haven and Connecticut. The collection consists of newsletters, flyers, posters, and other printed material.
Bisexuality; Gay men -- Connecticut -- New Haven -- Periodicals; Gay men -- Connecticut -- New Haven; Homosexuality; Lesbianism; Lesbians -- Connecticut -- New Haven -- Periodicals; Lesbians -- Connecticut -- New Haven; Gender nonconformity; LGBTQ resource; Metroline; A Lesbian position
- Publications, 1972-2007; Series I
  Scope and Contents
  This series, arranged alphabetically by title, consists of publications, primarily newsletters, by or about lesbian, gay, bisexual, and transgender individuals and organizations.
  - CT Coalition Update, Volume 1, Issue 3 and Volume 2, Issue 1, 1998, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - The Directory New England (Boston, MA), 1981 Spring (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - The Force, Volume 1, Numbers 3 and 5 and Volume 2, Number 1, 1982-1983 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - The Griffin, volume III, Number 3, 1972 May-June (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Invert: The Journal of Gay and Lesbian Sensibility, Volume 2, Number 3, 1991 Summer (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Kwanzaa Project News, 1998-2000 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - A Lesbian Position: The Newsletter (New Haven)
    General
    Includes production mock-ups for some issues.
    - Volume I, Issues 2-12, 1982 May-1983 March (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Volume II
      - Issues 1-3, 9, 1983 April-1983 June (Box 19, Folder 2)
      - Issues 4-8, 11-12, 1983 July-1984 March (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Volume III
      - Issues 1-11, 1984 April-1985 February (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Issue 12, 1985 March (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Volume IV
      - Issues 1, 4, 1985 Apr, July (Box 19, Folder 4)
      - Issues 2-3, 5-12, 1985 May-1986 March (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Volume V
      - Issues 1-8, 10-11, 1986 April-1987 February (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Issues 9, 12, 1986, Dec, 1987 March (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Volume 6
      - Issues 1-5, 9, 1987 Apr, 1987 December (Box 20, Folder 2)
      - Issues 6-8, 10-12, 1987 September-1988 March (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Volume 7
      - Issues 1-5, 7-12, 1988 April-1989 March (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Issue 6, 1988 September (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Volume 8, Numbers 1-7, 9, 11-12, 1989 April-1990 March (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Volume 9, Numbers 1-[9] [cover of number 9, December is mis-labeled as number 7, October], 11-12, 1990 April-1991 March (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Volume 10, Numbers 1-3, 12, 1991 April-1992 March (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Volume 11, Numbers 1-6, 8-9, 11-12, 1992 April-1993 March (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Volume 12, 1993 April-1994 March (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Volume 13, 1994 April-1995 March (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Volume 14, Numbers 1-2, 4-12, 1995 April-1996 March (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Volume 15 [13 issues] [cover of issue 7, October is mis-labeled as issue 6, September], 1996 April-1997 April (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Volume 16, Numbers 2-8 [no number 1; see numer 13 of volume 15], 10-12, 1997 May-1998 March (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Volume 17
      - Numbers 1-2, 4-11, 1998 April-1999 February (Box 2, Folder 20)
      - Number 12, 1999 March (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Volume 18
      - Numbers 3, 10-12, 1999 June-2000 March (Box 2, Folder 21)
      - Numbers 1-[2] [cover of number 2, May is mis-labeled as number 1, May], 4, 6, 8, 1999 April-November (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Volume 19
      - Numbers 1-2, 2000 April-May (Box 2, Folder 22)
      - Numbers 4, [5?] [cover of number 5 Aug is mis-labeled as number 4 Aug], 9-12, 2000 July-2000 December (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Volume 20, Numbers 3-4, 9-11, 2001 March-2001 November (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Volume 21, Numbers 1-6, 2002 January-202 June (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - MECA Advocate, Volume 1, Issue 1 [Multi-Ethnic Cultural Awareness Center, Urban League of Greater Hartford, Inc.], 2000 May (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - MCC News [Metropolitan Community Church, Connecticut Valley], 1978 May-June (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Men of All Colors Together [Connecticut]
    - Volume III, Numbers 2, 4-12, 1987-1988 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Volume IV, Numbers 1, 3-12, 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Volume V, Numbers 2-7, 9-11, 1989-1999 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Volume VI, Numbers 1-7, 9-10, 12, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Volume VII, Numbers 1-5, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Volume VIII, Numbers 1-5, 7, 11, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Metroline
    - Volume 6
      - Numbers 3-12, 1983 March 1- August 1 (Box 17, Folder 1)
      - Number 14, 1983 September 1 (Box 3, Folder 31)
      - Number 15, 1983 September 15 (Box 17, Folder 2)
      - Number 16, 1983 October 1 (Box 3, Folder 32)
      - Numbers 17-19, 1983 October 15-November 12 (Box 17, Folder 3)
      - Number 20-21, 1983 November 25-December 19 (Box 3, Folder 33)
      - Number 22, 1983 December 23 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Volume 7
      - Numbers 1-2, 1984 January 6-20 (Box 3, Folder 34)
      - Number 3, 1984 February 3 (Box 17, Folder 5)
      - Numbers 5-8 [cover of number 6, March 15, is mis-labeled as number 5], 1984 March 2-April 27 (Box 3, Folder 35)
      - Numbers 10-11, 13, 1984 May 25-June 8, June 22 (Box 17, Folder 6)
      - Number 17, 1984 August 31 (Box 3, Folder 36)
      - Number 18, 1984 September 21 (Box 17, Folder 7)
      - Number 19, 1984 October 5 (Box 3, Folder 37)
      - Numbers 20-21, 1984 October 19-November 2 (Box 17, Folder 8)
      - Number 22, 1984 November 16 (Box 3, Folder 38)
      - Number 25, 1984 December 28 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Volume 8
      - Number 2-12, 1985 April 5-December 1 (Box 3, Folder 40 - 41)
    - Volume 9
      - Issues 1-18, 1986 January 17-September 26 (Box 3, Folder 42 - 44)
      - Issues 19-22, 1986 October 10-November 21 (Box 4, Folder 45)
      - Issue 23, 1986 December 5 (Box 17, Folder 9)
      - Issue 24, 1986 December 19 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Volume 10
      - Number 1, 1987 January 9 (Box 17, Folder 10)
      - Number 5, 1987 March 6 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Volume 12
      - Number 1, 1989 January 6 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Volume 13
      - Numbers 20-21, 1990 October 19-November 2 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Volume 14
      - Number 1, 1991 January 11 (Box 4, Folder 47)
      - Number 9, 1991 May 3 (Box 17, Folder 13)
      - Number 13, 1991 July 12 (Box 4, Folder 48)
      - Number 16, 1991 August 23 (Box 4, Folder 49)
      - Numbers 19-23, 1991 October 4-November 29 (Box 4, Folder 50 - 51)
    - Volume 15
      - Number 5, 1992 March 6 (Box 4, Folder 52)
      - Numbers 21-22, 1992 October 29-November 12 (Box 4, Folder 53)
      - Number 25, 1992 December 24 (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Volume 16
      - Numbers 1-3, 1993 January 7-February 4 (Box 4, Folder 55)
      - Numbers 10-12, 1993 May 13-June 10 (Box 4, Folder 56)
      - Number 14, 1993 July 8 (Box 4, Folder 57)
      - Number 16, 1993 August 5 (Box 4, Folder 58)
      - Numbers 19-26, 1993 September 16-December 23 (Box 4, Folder 59 - 60)
    - Volume 17
      - Numbers 1-4, 1994 January 6-February 17 (Box 5, Folder 61)
      - Numbers 6-25, 1994 March 17-December 27 (Box 5, Folder 62 - 66)
    - Volume 18
      - Issues 1-9, 1995 January 5-May 10 (Box 5, Folder 67 - 68)
      - Numbers 11-16 [number 15, Jul 27-Aug 9, cover mis-dated Jul 13-26], 1995 May 11-August 23 (Box 6, Folder 69 - 70)
      - Number 18, 1995 September 7-20 (Box 6, Folder 71)
      - Numbers 20-25 [number 24 is mis-labeled as number 23 on table of contents page], 1995 October 5 - 1996 January 3 (Box 6, Folder 72 - 73)
    - Volume 19
      - Numbers 1-5, 7 [number 3, Feb 15-28, is mis-labeled as number 1 on table of contents page; no issue 6], 1996 January 4-April 10 (Box 6, Folder 74 - 75)
      - Numbers 9-15, 1996 April 25- July 31 (Box 6, Folder 76 - 77)
      - Numbers 17-24, 1996 August 15-October 29 (Box 6, Folder 78 - 79)
      - Number 25, 1996 October 30-November 5 (Box 7, Folder 80)
      - Number 27, 1996 November 13-19 (Box 7, Folder 81)
      - Numbers 29-31, 1996 November 27-December 17 (Box 7, Folder 82)
    - Volume 20
      - 1997 Jan 28-Feb 18 [unnumbered and number 6?] (Box 7, Folder 83)
      - Number 10, 1997 March 5-11 (Box 7, Folder 84)
    - Volume 24
      - Issues 1-6, 1997 May 15-July 24 (Box 7, Folder 85 - 86)
      - Issues 8-14, 1997 August 21-November 13 (Box 7, Folder 87 - 88)
      - Issue 16, 1997 December 11 (Box 7, Folder 89)
    - Volume 25
      - Issue 4, 1998 February 26 (Box 7, Folder 90)
      - Issue 9, 1998 May 7 (Box 7, Folder 91)
      - Issues 11-17, 1998 June 4-September 3 (Box 7, Folder 92 - 93)
      - Issues 19-21, 1998 October 8-November 5 (Box 8, Folder 94)
      - Issues 23-24, 1998 December 3-18 (Box 8, Folder 95)
    - Volume 26
      - Issue 1, 1999 January 7 (Box 8, Folder 96)
      - Issues 4-5, 1999 February 18-March 4 (Box 8, Folder 97)
      - Issues 7-16, 1999 April-August (Box 8, Folder 98 - 100)
      - Issues 17-24, 1999 September-December (Box 9, Folder 101 - 102)
    - Volume 27
      - Issues 1-12, 2000 January-June (Box 9, Folder 103 - 105)
      - Issues 13-25, 2000 July-December (Box 10, Folder 106 - 108)
    - Volume 28
      - Issues 1-16, 2001 January 11-August 23 (Box 10, Folder 109 - 112)
      - Issues 17-19, 2001 September 13-October 11 (Box 11, Folder 113)
      - Issues 21-24, 2001 November-December (Box 11, Folder 114)
    - Volume 29
      - Issues 1-12, 2002 January-June (Box 11, Folder 115 - 117)
      - Issues 14-15 [issue 22, Late November, is mis-labeled issue 21, Early November], 2002 July-August (Box 11, Folder 118)
      - Issues 17-24, 2002 September-December (Box 11, Folder 119 - 120)
    - Volume 30
      - Issues 2-4, 2003 January-February (Box 11, Folder 121)
      - Issues 5-19, 2003 March-October (Box 12, Folder 122 - 125)
      - Issues 23-24, 2003 December (Box 12, Folder 126)
    - Volume 31
      - Issues 1-20 [issue 12 cover mis-labeled as issue 11], 2004 January-October (Box 12, Folder 127 - 131)
      - Issues 21-23, 2004 November-December (Box 13, Folder 132)
    - Volume 32
      - Issues 2-7, 2005 January-April (Box 13, Folder 133 - 134)
      - Issues 9-24, 2005 May-December (Box 13, Folder 135 - 138)
    - Volume 33
      - Issues 1-7, 2006 January-April (Box 13, Folder 139 - 140)
      - Issues 9-10, 2006 May (Box 13, Folder 141)
      - Issues 12-24 [issue 23, Early December, cover is mis-labeled Late December], 2006 June-December (Box 14, Folder 142 - 145)
    - Volume 34
      - Issues 1-5 [issue 4, Late February, cover is mis-labeled issue 3, Early February], 2007 January-February (Box 14, Folder 146 - 147)
      - Issues 7-12, 16-[17], 2007 April-Jun, August-September (Box 14, Folder 148 - 150)
  - New Dawn [newsletter of the Metropolitan Community Church of New Haven], 1990 Summer (Box 14, Folder 151)
  - Bears and Hunters: Northeast Ursamen Official Newsletter, 15th Anniversay Double Issue, Volume 15, Issues 2/3, Circa 2007 (Box 14, Folder 152)
  - Radia: New Haven's Feminist Calendar and Newsletter [New Haven Women's Liberation Center], 1990-1991 (Box 14, Folder 153)
  - Sister: New Haven women's liberation newsletter, 1973 July-1979 February (Box 14, Folder 154-155)
- Organizations, 1978-2007; Series II
  This series, arranged alphabetically by organization name, consists of printed material such as announcements, flyers, poster, and programs. Publications are listed in Series I.
  - Connecticut Coalition for Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual and Transgender Civil Rights, 2000 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Connecticut Gay and Lesbian Film Festival, 2000-2007 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Poster, 2001 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Connecticut Gay Men's Choir, 1994-2002 (Box 15, Folder 3-4)
  - Connecticut P.R.I.D.E. [People Respecting Individual Diversity Everyday], 2002 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Connecticut Women's Education and Legal Fund, 2000 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - George W. Henry Foundation, 1978 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - New Haven Women's Liberation Center, 1986 March-1987 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Northeast Ursamen, 2006 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - The Theatre of Light and Shadow, "An evening of feminist theatre", 1979 (Box 15, Folder 9A)
  - Women and Family Life Center [New Haven], 2007 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Unknown, "Why Connecticut's Anti-Discrimination Laws Should Include Gender Identity/Expression", Undated (Box 15, Folder 11)